# Esteban Garcia



estebangarcia2121@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/estebangarcia21



(916) 807-1663



https://www.estebangarcia.dev/

# Summary

Professional developer who is passionate about Computer Science with 8 years of total experience programming, one of them being professional experience. Experienced with building front-end and back-end projects using React, Typescript, NodeJS, NextJS, HTML, CSS, Ruby on Rails, and other similar technologies. Recently lead the development of a greenfield project at a fast-paced startup using Typescript, presenting work directly to the CEO and engineering lead.

# **Experience**



### Software Engineer

Streamline™

Jun 2022 - Dec 2022 (7 months)

My primary role at Streamline was to design, test, and implement new and scalable solutions for PDF accessibility such as automatic PDF remediation and validation to aid users with visual or auditory impairments. Using Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, GraphQL, React, Typescript, and AWS, I lead the development of this project and implemented the necessary backend and frontend changes (collaborating directly with the Product Manager) to aid in the delivery of this product to our users.



#### Software Engineer Internship

Streamline™

Jun 2022 - Jun 2022 (1 month)

As a Software Engineer Intern at Streamline, I was exposed to the Agile and SCRUM methodologies that every successful engineering team must be familiar with by participating in bi-weekly sprint planning and refinement meetings. I was in charge of presenting experimental code to the Product Manager, Lead Engineer, and CEO to scope out a PDF Accessibility Scanning project in NodeJS and Typescript.

#### 🔭 Software Engineering Club President

Franklin High School

Aug 2021 - May 2022 (10 months)

Taught the fundamentals and best practices of mobile and web development at my High School using React Native, Typescript, ExpressJS, and MySQL. Organized two teams of three developers at the end of the year to build the backend and frontend of a small mobile application.

#### 🔭 Game Development Club President

Franklin High School

Aug 2019 - May 2021 (1 year 10 months)

Taught aspiring developers object oriented programming with C# and game development with Unity3D at my High School. I also worked with the head of the Computer Science department to schedule meetings for the review of student progress.

# Computer Science Tutor

Franklin High School

Apr 2019 - May 2019 (2 months)

Provided hands on opportunities for a student to solve algorithms using C++, allowing them to earn their Associate's Degree in Computer Science from Sacramento City College. Strengthened the student's knowledge of procedural programming by working together to refactor existing functions.

### **Education**



Aug 2018 - May 2022

#### **Skills**

GraphQL • TypeScript • Ruby on Rails • Amazon Web Services (AWS) • Next.js • Node.js • React.js • HTML • Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) • Agile Methodologies